

LONG DIEN TRAN BAO

With 8 years of experience in full-stack marketing for tech products, including 4 years at the senior management level; I excel at leveraging multiple channels to maximize users engagement and product adoption. As a collaborative leader, I empower my team to engage and drive business success.

SKILLS

- Leadership & Mentoring
- Marketing strategic planning & execution
- Stakeholders management
- Business English communication



EXPERIENCE

FINAN (SOBANHANG) | Senior Partnership Manager | Jan 2022 - Sep 2023

The most popular business management platform for nano & micro SMEs in Vietnam

- Collaborated with partners to integrate their products and services into the SoBanHang SaaS platform.
- Developed and implemented marketing campaigns to drive revenue growth through partnerships.
- Created and managed roll-out plans to ensure successful adoption of partnership features.
- Coordinated with stakeholders to ensure smooth integration and operational efficiency.
- Utilized data-driven insights from CRM tools to optimize growths.

Partners: HDBank, MBBank, BIDV, VietinBank, MaritimeBank, VNPT, NeoX, Droppi, Selly, Huuk, AccessTrade, Best Express, MoEngage

PPCLINK | Senior Marketing Manager | Mar 2020 - May 2021

App publishers in utility & kids categories with over 04 millions DAUs

- Led a lean team to drive user acquisition, retention, and revenue growth across apps within Vkids & PPCLink publishers.
- Developed strategies to maximize user engagement and increase revenue through in-app purchases and partnerships.
- Collaborated with internal stakeholders to optimize marketing campaigns and enhance UI/UX.
- Enhanced brand familiarity and generate revenue by lead generation.

Achievements: 20% YoY increase in revenue; 10% YoY increase in DAUs

TOPICA EDTECH GROUP | Senior Marketing Expert | Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

The leading EdTech group in South East Asian

- Carried out new initiative marketing projects to create growth in revenue streams across Topica's products.
- Developed and implemented content optimization strategies for two projects.
- Managed media materials created by well-known YouTubers and tailored them to target specific audiences.
- Led teams in generating leads from paid ads and monitored sales performance.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure effective marketing execution.

Achievements:

- Edumall Thailand project: achieved revenue of 2 million THB with a 30% ROAS and generated 2,300 leads in pilot.
- Topica Native Vietnam project: achieved revenue of 500 millions VND with a 33% ROAS and generated 2,800 leads in pilot.

POPS WORLDWIDE | Senior Marketing Executive | Oct 2014 - Oct 2017

The leading digital entertainment company in South East Asian

- Collaborated with partners to excel at managing their YouTube channels to achieve target viewership & revenue by providing insightful content recommendations and channel performance optimization.
- New entertained contents roll-out marketing planning and collaborated with other stakeholders for excellent execution.
- Directly managed POPS-owned music content projects from scratches.

Achievements: 50% YoY increase in viewership and 5% YoY increase in monetization for every managed channels.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree in Business Administration Google Ads, Analytics & SEO badges Hoa Sen University

LinkedIn Skills Assessments

Content ownership & Asset monetization courses YouTube Certified Program